Guide to the James Jesse Strang Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Section D: General Correspondence
  - 511. GILBERT WATSON. ALS, dated Voree, Nov 13, 1849, to James J. Strang at Baltimore. 3 p. foolscap. (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - 512. GILBERT WATSON. ALS, dated Voree, Nov 30, 1849, to James J. Strang at Washington. 4 p. foolscap. (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - 513. ALDEN HALE. ALS, dated [Voree] Dec 30, 1849, to James J. Strang at Washington. With postscript by Gilbert Watson, dated Dec 31, 1849. 6 p. foolscap. (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - 514. JOHN COLE. ALS, dated [Voree], Dec 3, 1849, to James J. Strang, with postscript by Gilbert Watson. 2 p. foolscap. (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - 515. GILBERT WATSON. ALS, dated Voree, Feb 11, 1850, to James J. Strang at Baltimore. (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - 516. GILBERT WATSON. ALS, dated Voree, Apr 16, 1850, to James J. Strang at Beaver Island. 1 p. 8vo. (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - 517. WINGFIELD WATSON. AL, dated Lox [?], [ ], Feb 16, 1862, to Gilbert Watson. 2 p. foolscap. (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - 518. D. R. WHIPPLE. ALS, dated Washington, Nov 21, 1849, to James J. Strang at Baltimore. 1 p. 8vo. (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - 519. D. R. WHIPPLE. ALS, dated Washington, Dec 28 [and 29], 1849, to A. P. Hosmer at Baltimore. 3 p. 8vo. (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - 520. D. R. WHIPPLE. ALS, dated Washington, Jan 9, 1850, to James J. Strang. 2 p. 8vo. (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - 521. D. R. WHIPPLE. ALS, dated Washington, Mar 11, 1850, to James J. Strang. 1 p. foolscap. (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - 522. D. R. WHIPPLE. ALS, dated Washington, Apr 10, 1850, to James J. Strang. 1 p. foolscap. (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - 523. D. R. WHIPPLE. ALS, dated Parkersburg, W. Va., Mar 29, 1869, to unnamed sister [in the Church]. 4 p. foolscap. (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - 524. DAVID WILCOX. ALS, dated Shelby [Mich.?], Apr 14, 1846, to James J. Strang at Burlington, Wis. 2 p. foolscap. (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - 525. C. WILKIE. ALS, dated New York, Jun 15, 1856, to James J. Strang at Beaver Island. l p. foolscap. (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - 526. G. WILLIAMS. ALS, dated Detroit, Dec 3, 1849, to James J. Strang at Washington. l p. 8vo. (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - 527. SAMUEL WILLIAMS. ALS, dated Newark Ill., Jan 26, 1851, to James J. Strang at Voree. l p. foolscap. (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - 528. J. [?] H. Wilson. ALS, dated Baltimore, Dec 26, 1849, to James J. Strang. 1 p. 8vo. (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - 529. ALONZO WINSOR. ALS, dated Perry, Ill., Apr 29, 1846, to James J. Strang at Burlington. 1 p. foolscap. (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - 530. ALONZO WINSOR. ALS, dated Perry, Ill., Jun 13, 1846, to James J. Strang at Voree. 1 p. foolscap. (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - 531. HENRY WORKMAN. ALS, dated Allegheny City, Pa., Feb 12, 1850, to James J. Strang at Voree. 1 p. foolscap. (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - 532. B. G. WRIGHT. ALS, dated Burlington, Sep 13, 1849, to James J. Strang at Buffalo. l p. 8vo. (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - 533. B. G. WRIGHT. ALS, dated [Burlington, Wis.,] Sep 18, 1849], to James J. Strang at Buffalo. 1 p. 8vo. (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - 534. B. G. WRIGHT. ALS, dated Voree, Dec 8, 1849, to James J. Strang at Washington. 1 p. foolscap. (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - 535. B. G. WRIGHT. ALS, dated Voree, Jan 29, 1850. 4 p. foolscap. (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - 536. B. G. WRIGHT. ALS, dated Voree, Feb 14, 1850, to James J. Strang at New York City. 1 p. foolscap. (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - 537. B. G. WRIGHT. ALS, dated [Voree,] Apr 3, 1850, to James J. Strang at Buffalo. 2 p. foolscap. (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - 538. B. G. WRIGHT. ALS, dated Voree, Apr 17, 1850, to James J. Strang at Beaver Island. 2 p. 8vo. (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - 539. B. G. WRIGHT. ALS, dated Voree, Apr 25, 1850, to James J. Strang at Beaver Island. 1 p. foolscap. (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - 540. B. G. WRIGHT. ALS, dated Voree, Jul 16, 1850, to James J. Strang at Beaver Island. 2 p. foolscap. (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - 541. B. G. WRIGHT. ALS, dated [Voree], Aug l, 1850, to James J. Strang at Beaver Island. 2 p. foolscap. (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - 542. PHINEAS WRIGHT. ALS, dated Propeler St. Joseph, Aug 7, 1850, to James J. Strang at Beaver Island. 1 p. 8vo. (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - 543. PHINEAS WRIGHT. ALS, dated Kosknony, Wis., Aug 23, 1850, to James J. Strang at Beaver Island. 2 p. foolscap. (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - 544. ALVAH YARRINGTON. ALS, dated Athens, [Pa.?] May 11, 1849, to James J. Strang, at Voree. 2 p. foolscap. (Box 2, Folder 46)
- Section E: Milo Quiafe's Research Files
  The material in folders 47-62 is uncatalogued. The following is a list of folder titles.
  - M.L. Leach "A History of the Mormons " with notes (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Clippings and Notes (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Covenant (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Extracts, Notes (I) (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Extracts, Notes (II) (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Biographical Sketch by C.J. Strang (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - G. Bates account of Strang's Trial (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Correspondence related to Quaife's research (Box 2, Folder 54-56)
  - Correspondence with Strang family-Quaife's research (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Strang family accounts of J.J. Strang copied by Quaife (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Notes and Correspondence-Quaife's research-Watson (I) (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Notes and Correspondence-Quaife-Watson (II) (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Correspondence-Quaife (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Quaife-Notes (Box 3, Folder 62)
- Calendar of the Strang Manuscripts (Box 4)